A Finding Aid to the Abbott Handerson Thayer and Thayer Family Papers, 1851-1999 (bulk 1881-1950), in the Archives of American Art AAA.thayabbo
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, circa 1861-1933; Series 8; (Box 5, MGP 2; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series contains photographs of Abbott H. Thayer, including two portraits of him, a photo of him with a group of people (possibly at Gerald Thayer's wedding), and a photograph of his plaster death mask. Also found are photographs of Thayer's studio, some of which include the painting he was working on at the time, his son Gerald, and other models. There are photographs of Thayer's home in Dublin, New Hampshire. Additional photographs are of his wife, Emma Beach Thayer, Ralph Waldo Emerson, and one of his former student Rockwell Kent painting outdoors. Also found are numerous photographs of unidentified people, most likely members of the Thayer family, and a few photographs of artwork by Thayer. Glass plate negative is housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Photographs of Abbott H. Thayer, circa 1861, 1900, 1915 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Thayer's Studio, circa 1895 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Thayer's Home, Dublin, New Hampshire, circa 1905 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Emma Beach Thayer, circa 1870, 1889 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Gladys Thayer Reasoner & Family (Photocopies), circa 1915, 1933 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Lyman and Grace Reasoner, circa 1919 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Ralph Waldo Emerson, circa 1860 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Photograph of Rockwell Kent, circa 1905 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Unidentified Portraits, circa 1860-1890 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Unidentified Tintype Portraits, circa 1870-1890; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 14-15)
  - Glass Plate Negative of Unidentified Man, circa 1890; (Not scanned) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 16)
    (1 glass plate negative housed in MGP 2)
  - Glass Plate Negative, 1 Glass negatives (Box MGP 2)
  - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1895; (Not scanned) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Tintype Photograph of The Sisters, circa 1884; (Not scanned) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Original Frame for Photograph of The Sisters, circa 1884; (Not scanned) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 19)
- Artwork, 1887 - circa 1940s; Series 9; (Box 5-6, 8; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series includes two drawings by Abbott Thayer, one depicting an angel and modeled by his daughter Mary. Also found is a large amount of artwork by children, including drawings by Gerald Thayer and other unidentified drawings and paintings, probably by Mary, Gerald, and Gladys Thayer, animal cutouts by Jean Reasoner Plunket, and other small painted cutout figures by an unknown artist. Also found are two sketchbooks, one belonging to David Reasoner, and the other probably belonging to his daughter, Jean Reasoner Plunket.
  - Drawings by Abbott Handerson Thayer, 1887, 1912 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 20)
  - Artwork by Gerald Thayer, 1889 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 21)
  - Artwork by Unidentified Children (probably Mary, Gerald, and Gladys Thayer), circa 1890-1900; (2 folders) (Box 6 (pam), Folder 1-2)
  - Painted Cutout Figures, circa 1904 (Box 6 (pam), Folder 3)
  - David Reasoner Sketchbook, circa 1910; (See Box 8) (Box 6 (pam), Folder 4)
  - Animal Cutouts by Jean Reasoner Plunket, circa 1940s; (Not scanned) (Box 6 (pam), Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook (possibly belonging to Jean Reasoner Plunket), circa 1940s (Box 6 (pam), Folder 6)
  - David Reasoner Sketchbook, circa 1910; (See also Box 6, folder 4) (Box 8 (pam), Folder 1)
- Scrapbook, circa 1910-1920; Series 10; (Box 7; 0.3 linear feet)
  This large scrapbook, compiled by David Reasoner, includes photographs and printed reproductions of paintings by Abbott Thayer, as well as a few newspaper clippings about his artwork. The scrapbook also includes a few notations listing the current owners of the paintings.
  - Scrapbook about Thayer Artwork, circa 1910-1920 (Box 7 (sol), Folder 1)